[Genius Girlfriend]
[Episode 11]
What's this?
It's a semi-automatic guitar.
Just press the corresponding keys
and it'll play the chords.
Give it a try.
That's so cool.
Let me try.
My fingers are so sensitive.
Don't even mention pressing down
on the strings—
just lightly touching one hurts like hell.
These fingers are pretty much done for.
I brought some band-aids.
Give me your hand.
Let me do it instead.
Does it hurt?
Be gentle.
Can we really count on Duan Qiyan?
We'll have to go for it.
It's all or nothing then.
Let's do it.
Baihui, are the monthly exam results
not out yet?
[Daily Study Plan]
My colleague Zhang's son is also
in No. 1 High School.
He said the results came out
a long time ago.
They're out.
I didn't do very well this time,
so I didn't tell you guys.
What rank did you get?
I got...
Fifth.
Fifth?
[Daily Study Plan]
What's this?
Lyrics.
You got fifth place and you still
have time for this kind of stuff?
- No, this is my...
- Does this have anything to do with studying?
Are you spending all day at school
thinking about these pointless things?
No, I just...
Don't bother arguing.
I'll go talk to
your homeroom teacher tomorrow
and find out what's really going on.
Tomo...
Dad!
[Celebrating the Anniversary
of Nanhai No. 1 High School]
Ms. Kong.
Jin Baihui's grades
have dropped way too much this time.
We're having a hard time accepting it.
Fluctuations in grades are normal.
We don't need to
let a single set of results get to us.
Besides, I don't think
the drop is necessarily
as serious as you think.
Well...
A drop is a drop.
Does it matter
whether it's serious or not?
That's because the pace in high school
is different from
middle school.
Exams are just a way
for us to assess students' proficiency
at this stage.
Jin Baihui is different from
other students.
She came back from Beijing,
s-so she should have adapted to
this pace a year earlier than
most students.
Yes, that's right.
I understand how you both feel.
I'll also keep a close eye
on my students' progress
from the teaching side.
But at the same time, I hope parents
can maintain
a more relaxed mindset.
Once an exam is over, it's over.
We still have the next one.
Besides, I think Jin Baihui
is a well-rounded student.
I think you should have confidence in her.
By the way, there's the school anniversary
celebration this afternoon,
with performances.
She'll be going on stage as well.
She'll be going on stage?
She's the lead vocalist.
The song their band will be performing
was written by her.
I heard them rehearse.
They were really good.
Those lyrics from yesterday—
you wrote them yourself, didn't you?
And you're even going to perform
on stage?
How could you keep
such an important thing from us?
Writing songs and rehearsing
must have taken up
so much of your study time.
Your grades have ended up like this
because you've been putting your heart
into these pointless things.
Who cares about some school performance?
Will it get you any extra points
on the college entrance exam?
- Dad, I...
- Baihui.
Your dad is right.
What's the point of taking part in
some school performance?
You only have so much time and energy.
If you waste it on things like this,
of course your grades will drop.
How many times do I have to tell you?
These little moments of happiness
you're chasing now
will only become obstacles
on your path to success.
You'd be better off spending that time
doing a couple more practice tests.
Be good
and go tell your teacher
that you won't be participating.
Mom, this performance isn't just about me.
It's the hard work of
many other classmates, too.
If I don't participate,
it'll affect them all.
How am I supposed to
get along with them then?
Get along?
You don't need to get along with them.
You only need to come in first place.
I know it's hard for you now,
but sometimes you have to feel this pain
to learn your lesson.
Mom.
About the school anniversary
this afternoon,
go explain the situation
to your teacher yourself.
Don't let us down again.
Have you decided
which ending pose you'll use?
As long as it looks cool.
That's for sure.
Jin Baihui.
T-These must be your parents.
Nice to meet you, Mr. and Mrs. Jin.
Come and watch our performance
this afternoon.
Jin Baihui sings really well.
So you guys are in a band together, right?
Yes...
Let me tell you,
my daughter Jin Baihui
isn't interested in these things.
- Dad.
- In the future,
don't involve her in these activities
anymore.
[Pursue Knowledge, Seek Truth;
Practice Diligently, Foster Innovation]
What happened?
What's wrong?
[Pursue Knowledge, Seek Truth;
Practice Diligently, Foster Innovation]
Lin Zhixia, Tang Tingting.
Come out for a bit.
Jin Baihui won't be performing
this afternoon.
Why?
Something came up.
I won't go into details with you.
If she's unable to perform,
is there anyone else
who can take her place?
Her throat hasn't recovered yet.
If there's no one to take her place,
the school may have to
cancel this performance.
Ms. Kong, I can sing.
Please don't cancel our performance.
Are you sure?
Alright then.
I'll try to help you.
But you have to be prepared.
Is our performance going through
some kind of ordeal?
Do we have to face 81 trials?
Am I Tang Sanzang or something?
Save your voice.
[Reading Corner]
What could I say?
It's about Jin Baihui, right?
We just ran into her parents.
I thought my dad was fierce enough,
but Jin Baihui's parents were both
on another level.
What's wrong with her parents?
Her parents wouldn't let her
perform this afternoon,
saying it would distract her
from studying.
I guess to them,
anything other than studying
is considered rebellious.
S-Should we encourage her to be
a little rebellious this time?
My voice still isn't back to normal,
and this song was written by Jin Baihui.
I haven't practiced it enough,
so I really don't have the confidence.
Forget it.
You guys didn't see the way
Jin Baihui's dad
shoved this program sheet at me.
I feel like if she goes against them
and performs,
her parents might actually beat her up.
Tingting.
Take some throat lozenges right away
and try to get your voice in better shape
before you go on stage.
You'll be able to pull it off.
Distinguished leaders,
honored guests,
dear teachers and students,
I hereby declare
the 50th Anniversary Celebration
of Nanhai Province No. 1 High School
officially open.
Up next is a performance
brought to you by Class 4, Grade 10
—a flute solo of "La Traviata."
Please enjoy.
[United in Glory,
Building a Brilliant Campus Together]
♪ The evening breeze rustles the willows
as the flute's melody fades ♪
♪ The setting sun sets
beyond the mountains ♪
[Notice Board]
Are you really willing
to give up just like that?
This song is your original work.
No one else can bring it to life
the way you can.
There are so many performances
at the anniversary celebration.
It won't matter if there's one less,
right?
We've been rehearsing together
for so long.
How can you just give up like that?
My parents asked me
to finish these 3 practice tests
this afternoon.
Have you ever thought about
taking a break?
Next, please enjoy
the classical dance performed by
the students of Class 2, Grade 10,
"Ode to the Orchid Pavilion."
Bravo!
Come on, guys.
We have no choice but to go for it.
Let's go!
Up next
is a song performed by Class 1, Grade 10.
This one is truly amazing.
The band is made up of members
from the first- and second-place teams
in the previous math contest.
Are you excited to see them?
Yes!
Next, please enjoy "Closed Loop."
[United in Glory,
Building a Brilliant Campus Together]
[Nanhai No. 1 High School Anniversary]
[United in Glory,
Building a Brilliant Campus Together]
[Nanhai No. 1 High School Anniversary]
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Enduring every second ♪
[United in Glory,
Building a Brilliant Campus Together]
[Nanhai No. 1 High School Anniversary]
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Enduring every second ♪
Let's go.
Jin Baihui.
Not everyone has a talent like yours—
that kind of ability
which can bring notes to life.
Your parents might say no,
but don't give up on yourself.
Because hidden within the notes you write
are the words
you're too afraid to say out loud.
Your songs and your words
deserve to be heard again and again.
This performance
is like a 10-minute break between classes—
a precious 10 minutes
you might not encounter
very often in life.
When the break is over,
we'll all return to our normal lives
and schoolwork.
Are you sure you want to miss out
on a memory that might stay with you
for the rest of your life?
The band is waiting for you.
Let's go on stage together,
take that break,
and then return to
our normal lives together.
Okay?
♪ Waiting ♪
♪ Every second is a test of endurance ♪
♪ Run away quickly ♪
♪ Testing with ulterior motives ♪
♪ If I could start over ♪
♪ Why not now? ♪
♪ It will turn around ♪
♪ Create accidents for accidents ♪
♪ Break out all the fake love ♪
♪ This dangerous persona ♪
♪ Please shut off your sense of
smell and sight ♪
♪ Your hearing and touch ♪
♪ Break out all the fake love ♪
♪ Who made the rules? ♪
♪ Not loving is the most alluring thing ♪
♪ It's my turn this time ♪
It's the school anniversary after all.
♪ Who's the one waiting? ♪
The atmosphere is what matters most.
♪ The hunter takes on the guise
of the prey ♪
The students in our class
really know how to pull off anything.
♪ There's no escape ♪
♪ From these familiar tactics ♪
♪ It's too late to surrender ♪
♪ A love that can never fall into sync ♪
♪ Another twist ♪
♪ We've formed a closed loop ♪
Let's get this party going!
♪ Break out all the fake love ♪
♪ This dangerous persona ♪
♪ Please shut off your sense of
smell and sight ♪
♪ Your hearing and touch ♪
♪ Break out all the fake love ♪
[Class 1, Grade 10—
Full of Vigor]
♪ Who made the rules? ♪
♪ Not loving is the most alluring thing ♪
♪ It's your turn this time ♪
[Class 1, Grade 10—
Absolutely Spectacular]
♪ Break out all the fake love ♪
♪ This dangerous persona ♪
♪ Please shut off your sense of
smell and sight ♪
♪ Your hearing and touch ♪
♪ Break out all the fake love ♪
♪ Who made the rules? ♪
♪ Not loving is the most alluring thing ♪
♪ It's your turn this time ♪
[Class 1, Grade 10—
Shining Brightly]
Absolutely Spectacular]
Why do I feel like
you're especially happy today?
Of course.
Duan Qiyan played the guitar beautifully,
Tang Tingting's little pony was adorable,
and most importantly,
Jin Baihui got to step onto that stage
with everyone else.
You have no idea
how moving it was to see you all
standing there in the spotlight.
So do you feel any regret
about not performing on stage?
The joy of being behind the scenes
is different.
Working bit by bit
to make the show happen,
and then seeing you all shine on stage—
that feeling is really special.
Let me help you.
No need.
♪ Wandering light wind
drifts past your pupils ♪
♪ You softly answer my quirky side ♪
♪ Such bliss to finally be understood ♪
♪ The moon drifts past the window ♪
♪ How am I to understand? ♪
♪ About you ♪
♪ The moment our eyes met,
my world came alive with color ♪
♪ Could this be how love begins? ♪
♪ These unspoken feelings
are so hard to figure out ♪
♪ The partiality towards me in your eyes ♪
Chunlei.
I feel like my voice is even hoarser now.
I was trying so hard to hype up the crowd.
I want bubble tea—
the biggest size they have.
Okay.
Tang Tingting.
Your show wasn't bad.
But as the lead vocalist,
you really dropped the ball.
If it weren't for Jin Baihui,
your performance
would've fallen apart, right?
So what?
It's a fact that
Jin Baihui sings really well, right?
Your show was pretty good too.
After all, not every show
saved time for the audience
to go to the toilet.
By the way,
I was chatting with some students
from Experimental High the other day,
and they told me
some girls from their school
had been scammed by scalpers on Tieba.
Someone from our school was scammed too.
I think her last name was Tang.
Didn't you go to that concert too?
Don't tell me it was you.
Of course not.
That's good.
I heard the tickets for that concert
were super hard to get
because there were so few available
to begin with,
and the perks were amazing.
Everyone who went
got an autographed photo.
Since you went,
you must've gotten one too, right?
Tingting, I'm a huge fan of Han Geng too.
Could you bring the autographed photo over
so I can take a look?
Of course I have to keep
the autographed photo safely at home.
I'll bring it to school sometime
and let you see it.
Sure.
I'll be waiting then.
I have to go.
We're going to celebrate later.
Bye-bye.
Let's go.
During the performance,
I thought I was watching
my idol's concert.
Gosh.
I felt like I was fangirling.
It was super cool.
Tingting, what did you say?
I can't hear you.
Let me ask you a question.
Shoot.
Didn't any of you notice my shoes?
These are my new lucky shoes
I bought specially for this performance.
I've been waiting all day and nobody's
asked me a single thing about them.
Designer shoes, right? And?
These aren't just any
ordinary designer shoes.
They're the reward Duan gave me
for making it into the top 5.
Don't you guys think his shoes
look a little too stiff?
Why don't we all just stomp on them a bit?
Good idea.
You guys better not mess with these.
This is the latest colorway.
I had my brother snag them for me
at retail price from a major city.
The owner of that trendy shop
behind our school even
marked them up to 1,000 yuan
just to buy these shoes from me.
I wouldn't sell them no matter what.
I don't even take them off when I sleep.
-Excuse me.
-On the back street...
What took you guys so long?
Hurry up and order some food.
-See what you want to eat and drink.
-Hello, order please.
This, and this.
Why are there glitters on your heads?
So pretty.
We went to return the props,
and a box in the storage room tipped over,
so some glitter and ribbons
got stuck to us.
Are there any left?
Yes.
It actually looks quite romantic.
Jiang.
How come your little cheeks
are flushing a bit?
N-No, they're not.
Don't be silly. I'm just really hot.
I feel like that little smile of yours
looks a bit devious.
Then show me your smile.
Hehe.
You think your smile's pretty, huh?
When it's served, I'll eat the meat,
and you eat the bread.
Get lost.
When's your throat going to recover?
If you keep talking like that,
I'm going to die laughing.
Don't make fun of Tingting.
Alright.
Everyone's here.
Let's all raise a glass
to celebrate
today's successful performance.
Cheers!
Come on.
-Cheers!
I'll have to stand up for this one.
We ran into Zhao Shuran backstage earlier.
After watching our performance,
she was completely speechless.
So she resorted to personal attacks
against Tingting,
saying that Tingting
had only played a pony,
had been scammed at a concert,
and the autographed photo...
Alright, that's enough.
I was having such a great day.
Just thinking about her makes me mad.
Why should you be mad?
Our little pony
did a great job today.
You have no idea.
When you appeared on stage,
you took the whole atmosphere
to another level.
You've officially inherited my legacy.
Thank you, Tang.
Yeah, you did a great job.
And Jin Baihui, you sang really well.
I heard many students in the audience
saying they were going to download
this song and listen to it at home.
Yeah.
You should write more songs.
Exactly.
In that case,
our band will be able to debut!
I'll pass.
I was just letting myself be rebellious
for once on stage today.
If my dad finds out,
I'm going to be in for it when I get home.
I understand what you mean.
You'd better stop writing songs.
Shen, do you remember
though we only met her dad
for the first time today,
he came in right away scolding us?
If you write another song,
I bet we'd both
be accused of instigation.
Look how cowardly he is.
I'm not the coward here. He is.
You're the coward.
If it weren't for your song,
our band wouldn't have put on
such a successful performance.
And your song's really catchy.
Every night when I close my eyes
to sleep,
your melodies just
keep playing in my head.
Well,
it's getting late. I'll get going.
You're leaving already?
So early?
Your bag.
-I'll walk you out.
-Bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
-Be careful on your way back.
Jin Baihui,
[Gentle Battle Hymn]
I've wanted to give this to you
ever since we first started the band.
Hope you like it.
Lin Zhixia.
Thank you for letting me be brave
this once.
I don't regret it.
You should thank yourself.
It was your choice to go on stage.
But now that the break's over,
I have to go back to facing
the same old routine day after day.
Maybe life itself
is your source of inspiration.
It's because you've experienced pain
that your lyrics carry so much power.
Actually, I revised those lyrics
several times.
The original version
even had swear words in it.
Thank you for not singing
the original version then.
I'm heading back now.
If I can't finish those papers tonight,
I probably won't be able to sleep again.
Good luck, Jin Baihui.
Thank you.
[Everyday To-do List]
[Math: 30 Olympiad Problems]
[Physics: 15 Challenging Problems]
[Chemistry: 20 Calculation Problems]
[English: Memorize 2 Passages
+50 Vocabulary Words]
[Gentle Battle Hymn]
[Everything has cracks;
that's where the light gets in.]
[The loneliness you feel now
is like a rainy day.]
[It will pass. When the skies clear,]
[you'll be able to go bask in the sun
with your friends again.]